in the book of matthew chapter 12 and
verse 34.
uh jesus here is speaking to the to the
pharisees and he says oh
generation of vipers
how can ye being evil speak good things
for out of the abundance of the heart
the mouth
speaketh for by thy words thou shalt be
justified
and by thy words thou shalt be condemned
jesus here is talking to pharisees and
he says to them
you are a generation of vipers now i got
a question for you
what are vipers that's right vipers
are serpents yes yes yes
he's saying you are speaking like a
bunch of serpents
so the bible is telling us that what
comes out of our mouth
is a condition of what is in our hearts
and then he says by your word you will
be justified and by your word you will
be condemned
which really means that it's by our
hearts that we will be justified
or condemned so check this out guys
satan wants to get
us to talk like him because he wants us
to be
judged and lost
satan wants to teach us how to talk like
vipers how does a viper speak
what is his language what is his
language
i want to share with you three aspects
of the language of satan the language of
the serpent
uh so that you can understand how to
identify his voice when you hear it
genesis 3 and the serpent summoned to
the woman
you shall not surely die so what is a
serpent
telling eve you're not doing anything
wrong
don't worry about it you are not doing
anything wrong
you have no reason to feel
guilty one of the ways we can identify
the voice of satan
a failure to acknowledge guilt
what about another aspect of his voice
notice with me job chapter 1 verse 9 and
the lord said unto satan behold all that
he has his in inning power
only upon him himself put not forth on
hand so satan went forth from the
presence of the lord
satan is an oppressor we're going to go
to isaiah chapter 14 verse 12.
the bible says here how are thou fallen
from heaven oh lucifer son of the
morning which how art thou cut down to
the ground which did sweep in the
nations
for thou has said in thine heart i will
ascend into heaven
i will exalt my throne above the stars
of god i will sit also upon the mount of
the congregation in the size of the
north
i would ascend above the height of the
clouds i will be like the most high one
of the three ways in which we can
identify the voice of satan is number
one
no guilt number two he is an oppressor
and number three
pride exaltation exalting oneself
above others all right if you're with me
so far
just let me hear a good amen even though
i can't hear you
follow those three things guys no guilt
oppression
pride so next the last verse in job 41
says this about leviathan
he beholdeth all high things
he is a king over all the children
of pride lucifer satan is a king
over the children of pride he is an
oppressor and he
fails to acknowledge guilt that's how
that's the voice
of the serpent now that we have have
that
uh understood notice this proverbs 10
verse 2 the bible says the wicked
in his pride doth persecute
who the poor the wicked in his pride
what does pride lead us to do
pride leads one to exalt himself or
herself
but also to persecute the poor
please keep following i need you to
watch this carefully
in the time of jesus satan
had basically trained the pharisees
and sadducees to speak his language
the pharisees spoke the language
of the serpent that's why in john
chapter 8 verse 43 and verse 44 jesus
said why do you not
understand my speech even because you
cannot hear my word
you are of your father the devil and the
lust of your father
ye will do in other words jesus is
saying look you don't understand my
language
because you're not of me you're of your
father the devil
you understand his language what is his
language
pride oppression
and lack of acknowledgement of guilt
how did the pharisees do this i want you
to notice desire of ages page 241
when jesus referred to the blessings
given to the gentiles the fierce
national pride of his hearers were
aroused and his words were drowned
in a two multiple voices
all right did you guys catch that just
now when jesus
is speaking to his own people and he
speaks about the gentiles
the fierce national what
pride of his hearers was aroused
and it totally drowned out his words
the leaders of israel were speaking with
the voice
of the serpent let's read another one
scribes and pharisees had
separated themselves from god by their
national pride
so if i'd ask you a question based upon
what we just read what
separated the scribes and pharisees from
god your answer is gonna be
their national pride
remember guys pride goes before
destruction and a holy spirit before
fall
pride is the language of the devil
christ would receive the service of
learned men
and of the great men if they would join
themselves to him but christ could not
join himself to them
for they were not right they were filled
with self-sufficiency and self-esteem
seeking constantly for the supremacy
spurning everything that did not bear
the appearance of worldly wisdom and
national pride and religious
exclusiveness
once again i want you to focus on
pride it is the language of satan
all right it is the language of satan
not only did they speak pride
but notice what else they did in acts
chapter 8 verse 1 the bible says and
saul this is before his conversion was
consenting unto his death
and at that time there was a great
persecution
and after saul consents unto the stoning
of stephen the bible says at that time
there was a great persecution against
the church
which was at jerusalem who was doing the
persecuting
right it was the leaders of israel
they were persecuting the christian
church
so watch this not only did they exercise
pride but they were also oppressors
persecuting the church remember
the language of the serpent i need you
to be able to identify
serpent talk the language of the serpent
is pride and oppression
and a failure to acknowledge guilt
john 19 verse 40. some of the pharisees
which were there with him heard these
words and said up to him
are we blind also jesus said unto them
if you are blind you should have no sin
but now you say we see therefore your
sin remains in other words jesus is
telling the pharisees listen
your failure to acknowledge your need to
acknowledge your guilt
leads you to be blind satan in heaven
refused to acknowledge he had done any
wrong
he refused to repent what wrong
what sin what guilt the voice
of the serpent is oppression
denial of guilt and pride
supremacy the bible says and i stood
upon the sand of the sea and saw a beast
rise up out of the sea
and the beast which i saw was likened to
a bear onto a leopard
and his feet were at the feet of a bear
and his mouth as a mouth of a lion
and the dragon gave him his power and
his seat
and great authority so i need you to
watch this carefully okay
because we understand who this sea beast
is
he rules for 1260 years
during the dark ages and the bible says
that the dragon gave him
his power the dragon
gave him his power so if i were to ask
you was the dragon speaking
through this beast what do you think
what do you think the answer would be
absolutely the dragon the serpent
was speaking through this beast
in revelation 13 verse 7 the bible says
and it was given unto him this beast
to make war with the saints and to
overcome them
and power was given to him over all
kindreds tongues and nations
so the bible tells us that that this
beast
that reigned during 1260 years was a
persecuting power it
oppressed people are you with me
that's during the dark ages so we have
one characteristic
it was an oppressive power what about
pride
according to second thessalonians
chapter 2 verse 3 the bible says let no
man deceive you by any means
who opposes and exalteth himself
above all that is called god so let me
ask you did this same power
exalt himself was there a pride issue
there
very good guys so we're seeing that this
beast that ruled during the 1260 years
oppressed and it also
had pride exalted itself in john 16
verse 2 he was ultimately speaking about
things to happen way in the future
specifically during the dark ages and he
said they shall put you
my enemies shall put you out of the
synagogues yeah the time is coming
whosoever kills you will think that he
is doing god's
service let me ask you a question did
persecution happen during these 260
years
absolutely the answer is yes did the
papacy who did the persecuting
think they were doing anything wrong
absolutely not
did they think there was any need for
repentance absolutely not
are you catching the idea oppression
pride and a failure
to acknowledge wrong doing